Contact Information email: ikuperwajs@nyu.eduweb: ionatankuperwajs.github.io

**phone:** 425-283-2084

### Research Interests

My research interests lie at the intersection of cognition and computation. I primarily use tools from artificial intelligence and reinforcement learning to infer what algorithms people use to plan sequences of actions in complex environments. My thesis work is on developing a normative framework for meta-planning and training deep neural networks to reproduce human play in a large-scale combinatorial game.

#### Education

## Ph.D. Candidate in Neural Science

2018-Present

New York University (New York, NY) Systems, Cognition, and Computation Track

## B.A. in Neuroscience, Computer Science, & Mathematics

2014-2018

Macalester College (St. Paul, MN)

Honors in Mathematics, Magna Cum Laude

#### **Publications**

#### **Preprints**

• van Opheusden, B., Galbiati, G., **Kuperwajs, I.**, Bnaya, Z., Li, Y., & Ma, W.J. (2021). Revealing the impact of expertise on human planning with a two-player board game. *PsyArXiv*. pdf

#### Conference articles

- Kuperwajs, I. & Ma, W.J. (2021). Planning to plan: a Bayesian model for optimizing the depth of decision tree search. *CogSci.* pdf
- Kuperwajs, I., van Opheusden, B., & Ma, W.J. (2019). Prospective planning and retrospective learning in a large-scale combinatorial game. *Cognitive Computational Neuroscience*. pdf

# Honors & Awards

NSF Graduate Research Fellowship	2020-2023
CCN Trainee Travel Grant	2019
Henry Mitchell McCracken Fellowship	2018
Phi Beta Kappa National Honor Society	2018
Macalester College Neuroscience Outstanding Graduate Award	2018
Cosyne Undergraduate Travel Grant	2018
IBRO-Simons Computational Neuroscience Imbizo	2018
Macalester College Dean's List	2014-2018
Janelia Undergraduate Scholars Program	2017
MIAC Men's Soccer Academic All-Conference Team	2015-2017
NYU Center for Neural Science NSF REU Fellowship	2016
Macalester College DeWitt Wallace Distinguished Scholar	2014

# Teaching Experience

#### Teaching Assistant, New York University

• Mathematical Tools for Neural and Cognitive Science (NEURL-GA 2201) F 19

#### Teaching Assistant, Macalester College

• Algorithm Design and Analysis (COMP 221)

F 17, S 18

	<ul> <li>Brain, Mind, and Behavior (PSYC 180)</li> <li>Core Concepts in Computer Science (COMP 123)</li> </ul>	F 16 S 16, F 16	
Talks	Cognitive Science Society University of Vienna (Vienna, Austria) Planning to plan: a Bayesian model for optimizing the depth of decision	2021 tree search	
	Center for Neural Science Seminar Series  New York University (New York, NY)  Model-based and model-free decision-making in a complex planning task	2020	
	Concepts and Categories Seminar Series  New York University (New York, NY)  Human planning in large state spaces	2019	
	Artificial and Biological Computation Lab New York University (New York, NY) Combinatorial planning	2019	
Poster Presentations	Workshop on Big Data in Cognitive Science  Princeton University (Princeton, NJ)  Prospective planning and retrospective learning in a large-scale combina	2019 ge-scale combinatorial game	
	Cognitive Computational Neuroscience  Technical University of Berlin (Berlin, Germany)  Prospective planning and retrospective learning in a large-scale combina	2019 atorial game	
Outreach & Service	<ul> <li>Science Activism</li> <li>President, Science Action and Advocacy Network (ScAAN)</li> <li>Workshop on evidence-based advocacy, American Geophysical Union</li> <li>Workshop on science activism, Rockefeller University</li> <li>Panel on science activism, Growing Up in Science</li> <li>Academic Mentoring</li> <li>Ashley Yan, Stevenson High School Student</li> </ul>	2018-Present 2021 2021 2020 2021	
Leadership	Commencement Speaker Selection Committee, Macalester College Software Development Organization, Macalester College Varsity Men's Soccer Team, Macalester College	2018 2015-2018 2014-2018	
Skills & Service	Programming: Python, MATLAB, R, Java, C, C++, HTML/CSS, bash Graduate Coursework: math tools for neuroscience, machine learning, Bayesian and cognitive modeling, cellular and systems neuroscience Methodologies: behavioral modeling, reinforcement learning, statistical inference, deep learning Lab: psychophysics, fMRI Languages: English, Spanish, Hebrew Interests: photography, podcasting, travel, hiking, soccer, basketball, anime, coffee		